I am a journalist and I am an immigrant and these two conditions define me
我是一名记者，也是一名移民，这两个条件定义了我
I was born in Mexico but more than half of my life has been reported in the
我出生在墨西哥，但据报道，我有超过半数的生命
united states a country created precisely by immigrants and as
美国一个由移民和
reporter and as a foreigner I have learned that neutrality
记者，作为外国人，我了解到中立
Silence and fear are not the best options for journalism and for the
沉默和恐惧不是新闻事业和新闻工作者的最佳选择。
life neutrality is often a
生活中立通常是
excuse journalists use to hide in our true
借口记者用来掩盖我们的真实
responsibility and what is that responsibility
责任，那是什么责任
questioning and challenging those in power that is what journalism is for
质疑和挑战当权者是新闻业的目的
the great wonder of journalism questions and defies the powerful
新闻事业的伟大奇迹，无视强大的力量
of course we have the obligation to report reality as it is not
当然，我们有义务报告现实，因为事实并非如此
as we would like it to be in this sense, I agree with the
正如我们希望的那样，我同意
principle of objectivity and a house is blue
客观性原则，房子是蓝色的
I say it's blue if there are a million unemployed said there are a million but
我说如果有一百万人失业，那是蓝色。
neutrality is not necessarily going to lead me to the truth even if it is
中立不一定会引导我去了解事实，即使事实是
rigorously scrupulous and I presented to you the two parts of a
严格谨慎，我向您介绍了
liberal and conservative democrat and republican news
自由保​​守派民主党和共和党新闻
the government and the opposition in the end that does not guarantee me nor does it guarantee us that
政府和反对派最终并不能保证我，也不能保证我们
let's know what is true and what is not true
让我们知道什么是正确的，什么是不正确的
life is much more complex and I think journalism should reflect
生活要复杂得多，我认为新闻应该反映
precisely that complexity let me tell you one thing I refuse
正是这种复杂性让我告诉你我拒绝的一件事
make a tape recorder I did not become a journalist to make a
制作磁带录音机我没有成为新闻记者来制作
tape recorder well I know what they are going to tell me nobody uses tape recorders in days
磁带录音机很好，我知道他们会告诉我什么，几天之内没有人使用磁带录音机
So I refuse to take out my cell phone and hit the record button and point it
所以我拒绝拿出我的手机，点击录音按钮并指向它
in front of me like they were a concert like a fan in a
在我面前就像他们是一场音乐会一样
concert this is not true journalism
演唱会这不是真正的新闻
Contrary to what many journalists think, all the time we are
与许多记者的想法相反，我们一直都在
making value judgments ethical and moral judgments and we are always making
进行价值判断，道德和道德判断，我们一直在做
highly personal and extraordinarily subjective decisions by
高度个人化和非常主观的决定
For example, what happens if you have to cover a dictatorship like that of August Pinochet in
例如，如果您必须承担像奥古斯特·皮诺切特（August Pinochet）这样的独裁政权，
Chile or Fidel Castro's in Cuba will report only what he wanted in general and
智利或古巴的菲德尔·卡斯特罗（Fidel Castro）将只报告他总体上想要的
the commander or you are going to face them, what happens if you find out that in your country
指挥官，或者您将要面对他们，如果您发现自己所在的国家会发生什么？
or in the next country students are disappearing and
或在下一个国家，学生正在消失，
clandestine graves appearing or millions disappearing the budget and
秘密坟墓的出现或数百万人的预算消失了，
magically appearing billionaire ex-presidents you're going to just give the
神奇地出现的亿万富翁前总统，你只会给
official version or what happens if you have to cover the presidential elections of
官方版本，或者如果您必须报道总统选举，会发生什么
the main superpower and one of the candidates makes racist comments
主要超级大国和其中一名候选人发表种族主义言论
sexist and xenophobic that happened to me and I want to tell you what I did
发生在我身上的性别歧视和仇外心理，我想告诉你我做了什么
but before explaining where I come from so that they understand what my reaction was
但在解释我来自哪里之前，让他们了解我的反应是什么
What if in Mexico City about the oldest of five brothers and the truth that
如果在墨西哥城大约有五个兄弟中的最年长的和那个事实
There was not enough money in the house to pay all the school fees.
房子里没有足够的钱来支付所有的学费。
university so I studied in the mornings and worked in the afternoons and
大学，所以我早上学习，下午工作，
after a long time they gave me a job that a reporter has always looked for
很长一段时间后，他们给了我一份记者一直在寻找的工作
television was a great opportunity but in my third report I was
电视是一个很好的机会，但在我的第三次报告中，我
happened to criticize the president and question the lack of democracy in
碰巧批评总统，并质疑总统缺乏民主
Mexico from 1929 to 2000 in Mexico there was pure fraud
墨西哥从1929年到2000年在墨西哥存在纯粹的欺诈行为
the president in turn chose by finger his successor and that was not a
总统反过来选择了他的继任者，那不是一个
true democracy seems like a great idea to me
对我来说，真正的民主似乎是个好主意
reporting my boss to my boss did not seem so
向老板汇报我的老板似乎不是这样
great at that time there was a direct censorship
当时很棒，有直接的审查制度
from the presidential house of los pinos to the media and my
从洛斯皮诺斯总统府到媒体和我的
boss who besides being in charge of the program and that I also worked
负责项目的老板，我也曾工作过
He was in charge of a soccer team and I always suspected that they interested him
他负责一支足球队，我一直怀疑他们对他感兴趣
plus the goals and the news censored my report asked me to
再加上目标和新闻审查，我的报告要求我
will change I said no and then he put another
会改变我说不，然后他把另一个
journalist to write what I was supposed to say I did not want
记者写出我本来不想说的话
being a censored journalist I don't know where I got the strength to write my
作为一名经过审查的记者，我不知道我在哪里有能力写我的论文。
letter of resignation and thus at 24 years of age only 24 make the decision more
辞职信，因此在24岁时只有24岁才能做出更多决定
difficult and momentous of my life not only was I going to give up television
我一生中艰难而艰难的时刻不仅是我要放弃电视
but I had decided to leave my country I sold my little boy was a ramshackle
但是我决定离开我的国家，我卖掉了我的小男孩，真是摇摇欲坠
red volkswagen get the dollars and i said goodbye to my friends family
红色大众拿到钱，我跟朋友家人道别
of my streets in my five goals from mista jos and bought a one-way ticket
我的5个进球中我的街道上的马萨·乔斯（Mita Jos）买了一张单程票
to Los Angeles California so I became one of the 250
到加利福尼亚的洛杉矶，所以我成为了250名之一
millions of immigrants around the world
世界各地数百万移民
ask any migrant about the first day when they arrive at that new
向任何移民询问新移民的第一天
country and they will see how they remember absolutely everything as if it were a
国家，他们将看到他们如何记得绝对的一切，就好像这是一个
film with background music in my case I arrived in Los Angeles on
以背景音乐为例的电影我到达洛杉矶时
sun was setting and all i had a guitar a weed and some
太阳快要落山了，我只剩下一把吉他，一堆杂草和一些
documents I could carry everything with my two hands
我可以用两只手携带所有东西的文件
I have not felt that feeling of absolute freedom again and survive with what
我再也没有感觉到绝对自由的感觉，可以继续生存下去了。
what I had with the little I had to get a student visa was
我只需要很少的钱就可以得到学生签证
studying I ate a lot of lettuce and pal because there was no more and finally in 1984
学习时我吃了许多生菜和好朋友，因为没有了，最后在1984年
I got my first job as a television reporter in the states
我在美国当电视记者时找到了第一份工作
united and the first thing I noticed is that my colleagues in the United States
团结起来，我首先注意到的是我在美国的同事
they criticized and very hard the president in turn ronald regan and it did not happen
他们批评总统，但很辛苦，罗纳德·里根（Ronald Regan）并没有发生
absolutely nothing, nobody censored it, I thought it was discontinuous, and that's how it has been
绝对没有，没有人审查它，我认为它是不连续的，就是这样
for more than 30 years reporting with absolute freedom and if the treaty as
在超过30年的时间里以绝对自由进行汇报，如果该条约是
an equal despite being an immigrant until suddenly I had to cover the
尽管是移民，但平等，直到突然之间我不得不掩盖
past presidential elections in the united states on june 16, 2015
过去的2015年6月16日在美国举行总统选举
a candidate who would eventually become president of the states
最终将成为州总统的候选人
Unidos said Mexican immigrants were criminals
Unidos说墨西哥移民是罪犯
drug dealers rapists and I knew he was lying
毒贩强奸犯，我知道他在撒谎
I knew he was wrong for a simple reason I am an immigrant
我知道他错了，原因很简单，我是移民
Mexican and we are not like that in such a way that I did what any other reporter
墨西哥人，我们不像其他记者那样做
I would have written him a handwritten letter, requesting an interview and
我会亲手写信给他，要求面试，然后
he sent the letter to his new york tower the next day he was already at the office and
他第二天已经在办公室的时候就把信寄到了纽约塔。
soon he begins to receive hundreds of calls and texts to my phone
很快，他开始收到数以百计的电话和短信发送到我的手机
some more insulting than others I don't
比我不侮辱的更多
I knew what was happening until a friend came to my office and told me
我知道发生了什么，直到一个朋友来到我的办公室告诉我
they published a cell phone number on the internet, they were actually made here
他们在互联网上发布了一个手机号码，实际上是在这里制作的
There is the letter that they sent that they put the cell phone neither do they write it down nor do they
他们寄了一封信，说他们把手机放了下来，也没有写下来，也没有
bother because they already change it but but I learned two things the first is that
麻烦是因为他们已经更改了它，但是我学到了两件事，第一件事是
you should never never never give your donalson cell phone number
你永远不应该永远不要给你的donalson手机号码
and the second lesson is that I should stop being neutral at that moment
第二课是那一刻我应该停止保持中立
from then on, my mission as a journalist changed. I was going to face the
从那时起，我作为记者的任务发生了变化。
candidate and prove him wrong that it was not true what he
候选人并证明他是错的，这是不正确的
said about immigrants in the United States
说到美国的移民
let me give your details to 97 percent of all undocumented in the
让我给您97％未记录的所有数据
United States with new people less than 3 percent have committed a
新移民少于3％的美国承诺
felony or felony and how they say it in English and in comparison 6 percent
重罪或重罪，以及他们怎么说的英语发音，相比之下，只有6％
of Americans have committed a serious crime
的美国人犯有严重罪行
the bottom line is that undocumented immigrants behave much better
最重要的是，无证移民的行为要好得多
than Americans with this data and if a plan eight
比有此数据的美国人，如果计划八
weeks after I posted my cell phone or credited as
我发布手机或记为
journalist at a press conference of the candidate who would trace all the
候选人的新闻发布会上的新闻记者，他将追踪所有
polls and decided to face him in person but things did not work out
投票并决定亲自面对他，但事情没有解决
exactly as I had planned see
完全按照我的计划
[Music]
[音乐]
planet 51 says no that for the gospel
第51号星球对福音说不
you cannot and by and the vermillion type you cannot nineteen hundred malvo you
你不能，而且不能和朱红色类型，你不能一千九百年马尔沃
cannot be nice systems &amp; your blessing of floors there are days that are no more
不可能是好的系统，而您的祝福地板已经不再存在
it is
这是
After watching the video, the first thing I always think of is that the
看完视频后，我首先想到的是
hatred is contagious if you look after the candidate
如果照顾候选人，仇恨就会传染
Colgate and Univision tells me those are code words what it is telling me
高露洁和Univision告诉我这些是代码字，它告诉我的是
now get out of here one of his followers as if they had given permission
现在离开这里，他的一个追随者，好像他们已经得到了许可
He told me get out of my country without knowing that I
他告诉我离开我的国家，却不知道我
I am also a citizen of the United States after watching this video many
观看了很多视频后，我也是美国公民
Sometimes I also think that to break neutrality and it is a true
有时候我也认为打破中立是真的
break up you have to lose your fear then learn to say no I'm not going to
分手，你必须失去恐惧，然后学会说不，我不会
shut up I'm not going to sit down and I'm not going to go him
闭嘴我不会坐下也不去他
he not he is not the most powerful word that exists in any language and
他不是，他不是任何一种语言中存在的最强大的单词，
always precedes any major change in our lives and I believe that
总是先于我们生活中的任何重大变化，我相信
there is enormous dignity and it generates a lot of respect
有很高的尊严，并引起很多尊重
the power to separate and resist and say no bezel the holocaust survivor
分离，抵抗和拒绝大屠杀幸存者的能力
and Nobel Peace Prize since we lost unfortunately very recently to say
和诺贝尔和平奖，因为不幸的是我们最近失去了发言权
some very wise words said we must take sides
一些非常明智的话说我们必须站在一边
neutrality only helps the oppressor never the victim is absolutely right
中立只会帮助压迫者，永远不会使受害者绝对正确
journalists are obliged to take sides in certain circumstances
记者有义务在某些情况下支持
in cases of racism, discrimination, corruption, public lies, dictatorships
在种族主义，歧视，腐败，公共谎言，独裁统治的情况下
and human rights we must put aside neutrality and indifference
和人权，我们必须抛弃中立和冷漠
In Spanish there is a beautiful word that describes where we should be standing
在西班牙语中，有一个漂亮的词描述了我们应该站立的地方
journalists and the word is effectively counter-power to journalists graus
记者这个词实际上是反击新闻记者的权力
be on the other side of where the powerful are but if you are involved in the
在强者所在的另一端，但如果您参与其中，
bed with the politician if you go to the christening at the wedding of the
如果您在婚礼当天去洗礼，请与政客同床
governor if you want to be a friend of the president like the two to criticize
州长，如果你想像两个总统一样成为总统的朋友来批评
when it's my turn to interview powerful or influential people, always
轮到我去采访有权势或有影响力的人时，总是
think of two things that if I ask that difficult uncomfortable question no one else
想起两件事，如果我问这个棘手的难受的问题，别无他法
it will be and that I will never see that again
它将是，我将再也见不到
person then I'm not looking or looking good and have to do in the end if
一个人，那么我看起来并不好看，如果
I have to choose between being a friend or an enemy of the president is always
我必须选择是总统的朋友还是敌人，这始终是
preferable to be the enemy to finish I know that these are moments very
宁愿成为敌人才能完成我知道这些时刻
difficult to become a migrant and a journalist but now more than ever
很难成为移民和新闻工作者，但现在比以往任何时候都多
they need journalists who are willing at any given moment to let
他们需要愿意在任何时候允许的新闻工作者
aside neutrality personally I feel that I have prepared
除了中立之外，我觉得我已经做好了准备
By this time all my life when I was censored at age 24 I learned that the
到这个时候，我一生都在接受24岁的审查时，我了解到
neutrality fear and silence often become an accomplice
中立，恐惧和沉默经常成为帮凶
crimes and abuses and injustices and being an accomplice of power never the good
犯罪，虐待和不公正行为，是权力的同谋，永远不会是好事
journalism now at 59 years old I just hope
我现在才59岁
have a little bit of the courage and mental clarity that I had when I was 24 years old and
有点像我24岁时的勇气和头脑清晰，
so I will never be silent again, thank you very much
所以我再也不会保持沉默，非常感谢
and
和